一夜之间多了这么多?
All that from overnight?
都是Freamon上报的
All that from Freamon.
他今天一大早就出去搜查空屋子了
He's out early today rooting through empties.
你知道他是个什么东西吗
You know what he is?
他就是个辣手摧花的
He is a vandal.
他破坏委员会 他破坏我们小队
He is vandalizing the board. He is vandalizing this unit.
他是匈奴人 他是西哥特人
He is a Hun, a Visigoth,
他是在城门前渴饮罗马贵族鲜血的野蛮人
a barbarian at the gate, clamoring for noble Roman blood
顺便让我们的破案率一落千丈
and what's left of our clearance rate.
你这会儿又是在干嘛呢
And you sit here doing what exactly?
毒品致死案吧 可能
A hot shot, maybe.
审讯室里有个家伙  说他几天前有一剂致命毒品
I got a sack in the box, says he owns one from a couple days ago.
白衣巷
White Coat Alley.
你们这些人他妈的有什么毛病
What the fuck is wrong with you people?
所有人都他妈想无谓增加谋杀案的数量吗
Is everybody on a crusade to make more murders out of bullshit?
那个毒贩子招供了 Jay  他去了西区警局自首
The mope's confessing, Jay. He walked up to the Western desk to do it.
Eddie 至少你制造出一起谋杀案的时候
Well, at least when you go to manufacturing a murder, Eddie,
已经抓住了嫌犯 这一点我很是佩服
you already have a suspect in hand. I respect that part of your game.
其他人要多学学你
Oh, that others might learn.
1号审讯室里需要警员旁听
I need a witness for the statement in box number one.
哦 我拉个屎就去
Yeah. Let me dump my shit. I'll be there.
氰化钠
Sodium cyanide.
你是说 如果我们给那小子做一个全面毒检
You're telling me, if we do a full tox screen on this kid,
会发现氰化物的痕迹
he comes back positive for cyanide:
是的 我就是这个意思 知道吗?
Yeah. That's what I'm saying, okay?
快把我关起来吧
You need to lock me up
我杀了那男孩 是我干的
because I killed that boy, I did.
是我干的 是我干的 所以说...
I did it. I did it. So just--
快把我关进大牢 把事情结了吧
just lock me up and be done with it, all right?
你哪儿来的氰化物
Where'd you get the cyanide?
你病了吗 Bunky
You getting sick there, Bunky?
你最近一次服药是什么时候
When's the last time you had your medicine?
不 不 我已近不吸毒了 明白吗
No. No, I'm not getting high anymore, okay?
我再问你一次
Let me ask you again,
你从哪里弄来的氰化物 如果你说...
Where'd you get cyanide from? If you're saying--
- 操! - 对不起
- Fuck! - I'm sorry.
- 该死 喷到我袖子上了 - 对不起
- Shit. He got my fucking sleeve. - I'm sorry.
冷静点 我们去找东西清理一下
Just calm down. We'll get something to clean this up,
给你再来瓶汽水
and maybe a soda or something.
- 起码帮你补充点糖分 - 对不起
- Get some sugar in you at least. - I'm sorry.
他一旦平静下来 我就向他宣读他的权利
He settles down, I'll Miranda.
好的
Yeah.
操
Fuck.
RAWLS吃鸡巴
偷钱本事和我前妻的律师一样
Steals like my ex-wife's lawyer.
天啊
Jesus.
快上去把他放下来
Get up there.
- 快 快 快! - 马上就好!
- Come on, come on, come on! - Give me a sec!
打911 1号审讯室的蠢蛋刚才想自杀
Call 911. The mutt in box one just tried to hang himself.
火线重案组 第四季 第13集 本季终
the.wire.s04e13
謦灵风软影视论坛荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流 严禁用于商业用途
www.1000fr.net presents
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
-=风软FRM字幕组=- 翻译:smartHHP 校对:青色的花 时间轴:于小坏
Sync:于小坏@FRS
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
"如果有动物被困住了 打410-844-6286" --巴尔的摩传统
这个就不知道了
No idea on this one.
这个街区2个 Lanvale区3个
Two on this block and three off Lanvale.
几个尸体都会出现在一个地方
They cluster.
他们找到喜欢的街区 就会不断回去
And when they found a block they liked, they came back on it.
Gilmore对面 下一个街区有一具尸体
One on the next block, across Gilmore.
那就9具尸体了
That makes nine.
可怕的是我们这才只搜查了一个区域
Scary thing is we're only looking at one district.
可恶 才一个分区而已
Shit. One sector.
你觉得他们的行动范围有多大
How far you think they might have roamed?
要知道这点只有一个办法
There's only one way to find out.
失陪一下 我是Daniels
Excuse me. Daniels.
尸检进展如何
How we doing with Forensics?
这是副总警监的职责范围 不过我的理解是
That's the colonel's domain, but my understanding is
我们往所有房屋都派一队实验员
that we're sending a lab team to every house.
目前为止我们找到了9毫米弹壳
So far we're finding 9-millimeter casings.
尸检开始后
Once they start scoping at the morgues,
应该能找到对应的子弹
we'll probably have slugs to go with them.
至于其他线索 我们在所有尸体现场都大量拍照
Tracewise, we're laser-printing around every body
并用吸尘器搜寻毛发和纤维
and vacuuming every crime scene for hair and fiber,
可是 那些都是空房子
but, of course, these are vacants.
那么多袋灰尘  我们的实验员要花一年才能找出有用的线索
It'll take our lab a year to sift that many bags of dirt.
- 这些都是一个贩毒团伙干的吗 - 很有可能
- Is this all from one drug crew? - Probably.
- Marlo Stanfield的黑帮 - 我们对他们调查得怎么样了
- Marlo Stanfield's bunch. - Where are we on them?
直到3个月前 重案组都在监听这个贩毒团伙
Major Crimes was working wiretaps until three months ago,
- 后来叫停了 - 我们能继续监听吗
- but we came down on those. - Can we get backup?
在尝试中  不过Stanfield团伙可能换了接头方式
Trying, but Stanfield's people may have changed up the pattern.
副总警监 需要什么尽管提
Well, Colonel, whatever you need.
其实 我最需要的是巡逻队
Actually, what I need is Patrol.
巡逻部
Patrol Division?
刚才Freamon警探打我电话
That was Detective Freamon on the phone.
我们在Lafayette又发现2起  在Lanvale发现1起
We found two more at Lafayette and another on Lanvale.
天啊
Jesus Christ.
从发现第一起开始 我们就挨家挨户地排查
Now starting at the first scene, we've been going door to door,
可我们根本不知道凶手行凶范围有多大
but there's no telling how far the shooter wandered.
现在市里有15000所空房子
And with 15,000 vacants in the city,
我的人要花上几个星期才能全部排查过来
it'll take my people weeks to cover that ground.
他接了这个案子 就离权利的宝座更近一步
He brings this case in, he'll be closer to the throne.
听着 我才不担心Daniels
Look, I wouldn't worry about Daniels.
他离我的位子远着呢
He's a long way from my chair,
你也一样
as are you.
你的行动太早 暴露了自己
You made your move too soon.
的确
I did.
政治不适合你 还是干业务吧
Politics doesn't suit you. Stick to operations.
别再像刚才那样冒犯我了
And don't you ever cross me like that again.
把这个公布到所有报纸上
Get it out to all the bulletins.
Leander 回局里去  每次点名的时候都分发传单
Leander, go downtown.Run a flier for every roll call.
传单上详细印上图钉和螺丝钉的样子 行吗
Show them the nails and the screws in detail. All right?
你拿一些这种钉子 去五金店挨个调查
You grab a couple of those nails and hit all the hardware stores.
查出我们究竟应该寻找什么样的型号
Find out exactly what the model is that we're looking for.
- 你要我干什么 - Herc
- What do you need from me? - Herc.
我是认真的 去把他带来
I'm serious. Get hold of him.
他情况怎样
How's he looking?
挺好的 反正没比上吊前差
Pretty good, considering. No worse than before he hung himself.
你他妈的去哪里
The fuck are you going?
西区 Freamon又找到一具尸体
West Side. Freamon found another.
操蛋的Freamon
Fucking Freamon.
- 他需要转到医院吗 - 可转可不转
- He a transport: - Borderline.
血压和脉搏正常
B.P. and pulse are normal.
我们给他注射了氯羟去甲安定
We gave him Ativan for withdrawal.
嘿 你想去医院吗
Hey, you want to go to a hospital?
我问你
Let me ask you something,
什么样的人使用了一剂致命毒品
What kind of a fellow rigs up a hot shot,
还要跑到警局自首
then walks into a police station to talk about it?
谁干得出来啊
Who does that?
- 你需要我们等在外面吗 - 不必了
- You want us to wait? - No.
你脑子里在想啥呢 哥们
What is in your head, fella?
那剂毒品本来是想用来
The hot shot was for this motherfucker
报复一个经常暴打我的王八蛋的
that has been beating on me.
那男孩呢
And the boy?
他会偷吸
He was dipping.
这事我知道 我...
I knew he was. I--
我只是... 我没多想...
I just didn't-- I didn't think...
那孩子孤苦伶仃
The child had no one for him--
没有母亲 没有家人
no mother, no family.
他就像我一样流浪在街头
He in the street like I'm in the street.
因此我想...
So I tried to...
搞得我像不知道自己是个啥东西 对吧
Like I ain't know who I am, right?
搞得我像假装自己不是一辈子都在吸毒
Like I'm pretending I ain't been a dope fiend my whole damn life.
哥们 把我关起来吧
Just lock me up, man.
因为那孩子是我杀的
'Cause I killed that child.
那剂毒品不是给孩子准备的
The shot wasn't for the kid.
我们把这家伙放了
Let's throw this one back.
我们还没怪罪他呢  这个苦瓜脸的负罪感就超重了
This sad-ass motherfucker's carrying more weight than we'll ever put on him.
破案率岂不是又下降了
What about the clearance?
- 操他的破案率 - 放他走吗
- Fuck the clearance. - Cut him loose?
该死 他会跳楼的
Shit, he'll go off a roof or some shit.
运气好的话 他的跳楼案还该我接
My luck, I'll catch that call too.
要不还是送到Bayview的D病区吧  墙壁不能太硬的那种
Maybe D ward over at Bayview, something with soft walls.
小子 你疯了吗
Is you out of your mind, nigger?
你以为 同样的东西 我会付你两倍的钱吗
You think I'ma pay you twice for the same motherfucking package?
嘿 我和你是一根身上的蚂蚱
Hey, I'm in the same box here.
基佬抢了你们的 他也抢了我的啊
Faggot took my shit same as he took y'all's.
哥们 这可只能怪你的人
Man, but that's on your own people.
这事儿是你的人负责安保
Your guys was the ones doing security on this shit.
嘿 我的人和以前我们几十次的交易时一样尽责
Hey, they worked it the same as we did the last dozen shipments.
你们以前也没提出什么不妥的啊
Y'all was fine with it up until this, right?
的确没什么不妥  直到这个操蛋的使出这么一招
Ain't no one have a problem with it till the motherfucker gave us one.
Joe 我们就此进行了内部投票
Thing is, Joe, we calle a quorum on this,
投票的结果是你们来解决这件事情
took a vote that says it's your people need to make this right.
不 不 合作行动意味分享
No no, a co-op means share and share alike.
有福同享有难同当
You share the good and you share the bad.
好吧
All right.
既然你们这样要求  那我就大出血把货都给你们
I'll dig deep and do the full shipment if that's what y'all need,
可是以后别想再找我补货
But don't even think about coming back to me for a re-up after this,
因为等那好货色到了的时候
'cause when that good raw shit comes straight off the boat,
就只归我一个人
it's gonna be mine only,
反正你们现在是不能和我有难同当的
seeing as how y'all can't find the heart to stand with me now.
你们还想重新投票吗 再好好考虑一下
You want to quorum up again, think it over a little?
呵 我就知道
Yeah, I thought you might.
我会回话说我们需要一批新货 越快越好
I'll get word back that we need a fresh shipment, and right quick,
你们可以考虑考虑我们要怎样加强安保措施
and you can think about what we need to do to improve security,
确保不会再发生这样的事
make sure it only happens the once.
好啊 小子
What's up, young'un?
那次是你们谁管毒品
Which one of your people was in charge of the stash?
我是说 我想和他谈
I mean, I want to talk to him.
我侄子 我妹妹的儿子
My nephew. My sister's boy.
我不能出卖他
I can't give him up like that.
我做不到
I can't do it.
货被抢时 我有熟人在场
My connect had people there when the shit went down.
如果你不信的话
If that's what you need to make you believe,
可以去问他
you can hear it straight from him.
我们发了
We are rich.
这才像话嘛
That's what I'm talking about.
谢了 宝贝
All right.
Butch
Butch.
好哥们
My man.
好了 美女 悠着点 听到了吗
Right, now, girl, you set that off slow, you feel me?
消息传开以后 就会有人找上门来
'Cause word gonna get around. They gonna come back on you now.
切 才不会呢
Nah. None of that.
要是有人问起我的另一份工作
Yo, anybody ask about me on another job,
就说 "Kimmy退休了" 明白了吗
tell 'em, "Kimmy been retired." All right?
保重
Be easy.
和墨西哥人分成后 你还剩多少
How much you got left after splitting with the Mexicans?
大概26吧
26 raw.
多谢咯
Gracious.
该死 哥们 唯一的问题是
Shit, only problem, man, I'll spend the rest of my life
我下半辈子都得耗在街上兜售毒品了
trying to put that out on the street.
我不是毒贩 Butch 懂吗
I ain't no drug dealer, Butch. You feel me?
该死 我们这次偷得太多了
Shit, we just stole too much this damn time.
那我该怎么办呢 Butch
So, what am l gonna do, Butch?
嗯...
Well...
你可以给Joe打电话
you could come give Joe a call.
提出把货卖回给他
Offer to sell the shit back to him now
打2折
for 20c on the dollar.
Joe或许会觉得这很幽默呢
Joe would have found some humor in that.
反正你一定觉得很好笑
I know you do.
我知道应该按照申请人名单先来后到
I understand there's a waiting list.
事实上这孩子曾经被别的家庭收养过了
The thing is this kid has already been in a foster home.
是的
Right.
现在他的养母住院了 因此...
And now his foster mother's been hospitalized, so--
是的 不
Right. No.
我能不能和主管谈谈
Is there a supervisor that I can talk to?
点名我要晚去一些 先把这孩子安顿了
I'm gonna be a little late for roll call. Gotta get this kid settled.
社会保险部出什么问题了
What's wrong with D.S.S.?
我正和他们打电话呢 他们想让他去孤儿院
On the phone with them right now. hey're talking about a group home.
那又如何 要么你找一个监护人
So? Either you come up with a guardian,
要么他去社会服务机构 只有这两种选择
or he goes to Social Services. No two ways about it.
喂 喂
Hello: Hello:
我们需要你帮忙 穿上衣服
Need your help. Get dressed.
我被带薪停职了 正在等待审判
I'm suspended with pay, pending a full trial board.
恕我无能为力 Kima
Can't do nothing for no one, Kima.
管他们怎么说 这是警务
Fuck what they say. This here's police work,
我问你 你是警察吗
and I'm asking if you police.
好了 听好了 你们这些蠢蛋 这事儿很复杂
All right. Listen up, you mutts. This is complicated.
我是说 如果你上过大学
I mean, it isn't complicated if you went to college or,
或者 你妈怀孕时没有喝得天昏地暗
I don't know, your mothers actually stopped drinking
那么对你来说 也不算复杂
for a minute while they was pregnant.
可是对于巴尔的摩警局来说 这很复杂
But for Baltimore City Police, this is complicated.
言归正传 这是重案组
Anyway, this right here
调查西区空房子死尸案时
is for the Major Crimes homicide investigation
找到的重要线索
into the bodies being found in the vacant houses here in Western.
指挥官要市里的所有警员 排查各自区域的空房子
Command now wants all the districts to check every vacant in the city.
也就是说在你们的辖区范围内
That means you will need to go door to door
你们要挨家挨户地查看空房子
to every vacant house in your post
看密封房门用的是什么钉子
and look at what was used to board it up.
大多数应该是住房社区发展部使用的Phillips头螺丝钉
Most will have the Phillips head screws that H.C.D. uses,
就像传单上的这幅图一样
Iike this here on the flier.
如果你发现一所房子是用如图所示的
But if you see a house that's been boarded up
钉枪的钉子封住的
with nail-gun nails like these shown here,
立即呼叫你的区域队长
call your sector sergeant immediately.
你可以进入房子内 不过要是你发现尸体
You can enter the house, but if you find a body,
不要破坏现场 说完了
do not disturb the crime scene. All told.
我不明白的是  他们怎么就不肯在这件事上放过我呢
But what I don't understand is why they keep busting my balls about this.
我是说 部长那件事
I mean, Daniels gave me a slap on the wrist
Daniels都将我从轻发落了 是吧
for the thing with the minister, right?
Marimow刚要整我就被炒鱿鱼了
And Marimow got bounced just before he could fuck me up on anything else.
你确定是在这个街区吗
You sure we on the right block?
嗯 就在这边的路牙子附近把他们控制住了
Yeah. Put them on the curb right here, more or less.
接着你用钉枪
And then you fired the nail gun into the asphalt,
- 射在了他们坐的地方的柏油马路上 - 没错 就钉在小妞的腿旁
- right where they sat? - Yeah. Right next to the little broad's leg.
谁让内务处的混蛋们
So who tells these l.I.D. fucks
乱翻我的文件
to start running through my paperwork,
找什么乱七八糟的东西
Looking for who the fuck cares?
我是说 他们又不是逮着我偷东西
I mean, it's not like they caught me stealing
或虐待那些操蛋的 是吧
or brutalizing motherfuckers, right?
- 是吧 - 看
- Right? - Look.
嗯 看上去很像 就是这里吗
Yeah. It looks like it could be. Is that about right?
嗯
Yeah.
一定是挣脱了
Must have worked himself free.
我把钉子送到弹道科鉴定
I took them nails to Ballistics.
那里的科员说他可以匹配 任何那把钉枪里打出来的东西
Comparer said he could match anything out of that gun,
如果我们能找到钉枪的话 他还能匹配钉枪
and maybe the nail gun itself, if we could get it.
我是说 我知道他们会降我的级
I mean, I know they're gonna take my stripes,
不过他们应该不会就这样算了 是吧
but you don't think they're gonna go past that, right?
Herc 你到底干了什么
Herc, what'd you do exactly?
我未经警督允许 就从设备科拿了摄像机 最后还搞丢了
Lost the camera I took from l.S.D. without my lieutenant's approval.
那里来的证据
And what evidence I got from the camera,
我谎称是个线人给我的
I put to a made-up informant.
孩子
Son,
他们会把你往死里整  就像整一头租来的驴一样
they're gonna beat on your white ass like it's a rented mule.
操
Fuck.
那就迫使他签字
Then make him sign it.
那吃鸡巴的自作自受 我讨厌那个混蛋
Did it to himself, that cocksucker. I hate that bastard.
他管他叫吃鸡巴的
He called him cocksucker.
妈的
?
呼叫按钮会被你按坏的
You're gonna break that call button.
听着 我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry.
我不想打扰你 可我只能看4个频道
I don't mean to bother y'all, but I don't get but four channels.
只有4个频道可以给你看
That's all you get.
那我旁边的这位老兄呢
What about my man over there?
他有保险
He has insurance.
保险里包括了有线电视
And insurance pays for his cable hookup.
你被允许住院的唯一原因是你骨折了
Only reason you're admitted is that fracture.
一旦我们能放你走 你就马上走人
Soon as we can discharge you, we will.
你们这些毒贩子
All you gangsters
在我们的急救室里作威作福 好像理所应当
wash up in our E.R. like it's your due.
你们在外头兜售毒品 直到被枪击刀砍
You could stand out there slinging drugs till you get shot or cut,
我们给你们免费救治
have us put you back together free of charge
痊愈后你们继续贩毒 如此反复
so you can do it again.
- 毒贩子哈 - 哦 你不是吗
- Gangster, huh? - Oh, you're not that?
我查看过你的住院记录
I pulled your admissions.
90年代的时候你因枪伤来这里住院
You were here in '90 for a gunshot wound,
再往前推三年
and three years before that,
你因胸部砍伤又来住院
you were here for chest surgery for a cutting.
是的 很久以前我曾经是
Long time back, yeah.
看得出你现在还是
And I see you're still at it.
- Dennis Wise 我是Howard Colvin - 你是警察吗
- Dennis Wise, I'm Howard Colvin. - Are you police?
我... 曾经是
I... used to be,
现在我算是Tilghman的教师了
but now I'm a bit of a teacher up at Tilghman.
我遇上了个小麻烦  你认识西区的Carver吧
I got a little problem, and you know Carver over at the Western,
他说你或许能帮到我
he said that you might be able to help me.
我去了你的健身房  他们告诉了我事情的经过
I went up to your gym. They told me what happened.
你想让我告诉你什么
What is it that I'm supposed to know about?
关于Namond Brice
It's Namond Brice.
啊 他怎么了
Yeah. What's the problem?
哦... 见鬼
Oh... shit.
我刚开始照顾他
Well, I've just come to care about the kid.
你听说了吗 这回是小Kevin
You heard it was Little Kevin?
我看见一个警察 拿着他的项链从房子里走出来
I seen one of the police step out the household with his necklace.
裹尸袋里的是Kevin啊
That's Kevin up in there, yo.
这个操蛋的只是为杀人而杀人
This motherfucker be killing niggers just to do it.
明白吗
See?
他杀人只是因为他能杀人
Nigger killing motherfuckers just 'cause he can,
不是因为别人通风报信  不是因为生意上的事
not 'cause they snitching, not 'cause it's business,
只是因为他觉得杀人是很自然的事
but 'cause this shit just comes natural to him.
- 嘿 Bodie 哥们 - 我是说 小Kevin死了...
- Yo, Bodie, man-- - I mean, Little Kevin is gone--
这家伙什么感觉也没有
this nigger don't feel nothing.
那些死在房子里的人
And all them motherfuckers in them rowhouses,
- 他一个也不在乎 - Bodie 他妈的冷静点
- nobody mean a fucking thing to him. - Bodie, calm the fuck down.
操他的Marlo 哥们! 操死他
Fuck Marlo, man! Fuck him
以及所有这样草菅人命的家伙
and anybody that think it's all right to do people this way.
你听到了吗
You hear me?
操死你们这些操蛋的
Fuck all y'all motherfuckers.
他妈的放开我 哥们
Get the fuck off me, man.
袋子里是他的朋友
That's his friend in the bag.
那个家伙真他妈的有毛病
It's like that nigger ain't fit, man.
- 你看到了吗 - 去 把他关起来
- You see that shit, yo? - Go on. Lock his dumb ass up.
Attica! Attica!
- Attica! - 在封闭房屋内被发现的枪击受害者
- Attica! - the number of victims discovered shot to death
数目已达...
in the boarded-up buildings.
真是运气了我俩
How flattering for us.
这就把学校赤字事件挤下了头版
It knocks the school deficit right off the front pages.
凡事有利有弊 这就是利
There's your silver lining right there.
- 那些尸体是Royce的责任 - 学校赤字也是
- Those bodies are on Royce. - School deficit should be too.
的确 不过这是下一个财政年度的问题了
Should be, but that's a problem that's gonna play out in the next fiscal year.
那时候这事儿怎么都不归你管了
By then you're out of Teflon.
也就是说我拿了州长的钱  2年后
So I take the governor's money, and then two years from now
当我在华府郊区和选民们握手时 他们会说
when I shake the hand of any voter in the D.C. suburbs, they say
"哦 你就是那个用我的税金
"All right. You're the guy"
放弃学校体系的人"
"who needed my tax dollars to bail out your school system."
如果你收下他的支票 你就会失去Prince George和Montgomery的选票
If you take his check, you lose votes in Prince George's and Montgomery,
没有这些县的选票  你就不能在全国范围内战胜他
and you can't beat him statewide without the counties.
不过2年之后 当你成为州长的时候
But two years from now, if you're governor,
你就能将城市从安纳波利斯的淫威中解救出来
you can help the city from Annapolis.
他现在就是市长
He's the mayor now.
我承认我们不能解决城市学校问题
I agree we can't fix the city schools,
不过我们也不能让事态恶化
but we can't let them get any worse either.
回到安纳波利斯那里 接受他的给予
Go back to Annapolis. Eat his shit.
如果我们对当地学校失去控制
If we lose local control of the schools,
Nerese和老师们会要你好看
Nerese and the teachers will rip you,
可其他市民会认为 你这是为了孩子们好
but the rest of the city will see you did it for them kids.
孩子们没有投票权
Kids don't vote.
你这不是拿我们的货源冒险吗
Taking a risk with our supply, ain't you?
我是说 会见除了我们之外的人
I mean, setting up a meet with anybody other than us.
没办法 小子渴望安全感
Got to. The boy craves reassurance.
老大 你让Marlo那小子认识我们的联络人
Boss, you get that boy Marlo in line on our connect,
他可能绕过我们的合作 绕过我们
he might try to go round the co-op, go round us.
你懂吗
You know what I'm saying?
那些希腊人如此谨慎 你觉得他们会信任谁呢
Cautious as those Greeks be, who you think they gonna trust?
他们认识我们 而不认识他
They know us. They don't know him.
- 该死 - 看是谁来了
- Damn. - Look at this nigger coming round.
别激动 孩子 别激动
Easy, son. Easy.
我就知道能在这里找到你们
Yeah. I might have known I'd find you boys in here,
下班后还要开夜车
burning that oil after hours.
小子 我恨不得杀你两回
Nigger, I'ma kill you twice.
哦 你不想要你的货了吗
Oh? So you don't want your shipment, huh?
你想怎么样 说吧
Say your piece.
我碰巧有一批海洛因要卖
Well, it just so happens I got some heroin for sale.
在市场上 你们是买家 是吧
Marketwise, you fellas look like buyers. You feel me?
真不要脸
This some shameless shit.
哥们 我的游戏里没啥要不要脸的
Oh, ain't no shame in my game, dawg.
我是来做生意的 是吧 Joe
I'm here about the business. Ain't that right, Joe?
- 多少钱 - 2折
- How much? - 20 on the dollar.
1折 小子
10, nigger.
别逼我说2.5折
Don't make me say 25 now.
那是40万美元
That's 400,000.
要不这样 我们把你这个基佬拖到后屋
How about we take your faggot ass in the backroom
给你些颜色看看
and get into some diabolical brutality,
用老办法找到我们的货 如何
find our shit the old-fashioned way?
- 你懂吗 - 哦 我懂
- Feel me? - Oh, I feel you.
听上去不错
Sounds like a plan.
不知道行不行得通 Joe  你觉得Omar肯开口吗
I don't know though, Joe. You think Omar gonna give it up?
那就2折
20 on the dollar it is.
她走得怎样 Joe
Say, how's she ticking, Joe?
保持联络
I'll be in touch.
他认为
And he thinks
如果两年后我成为州长
I'll help the schools, help the city a lot more
我就能为学校为城市做更多贡献
if I'm governor two years from now.
我想 从这个角度上说
I'm thinking that way it wouldn't just be about me
拿不拿钱就不仅仅是我的事
if I don't take the money.
你这是在问我的想法吗
Are you asking me what I think?
我的想法是 你会做出正确的决定
I think you'll do the right thing.
真的 我没说谎
For real, I'm telling you the truth.
痒痒
Tickles.
你确定你想做吗
You sure you want to do this?
我不想伤害你
I don't want to hurt you.
不会的
Nah
Crutchfield警探 你有空吗
Detective Crutchfield, do you have a moment?
什么事 长官
Yes, ma'am.
出什么问题了吗
Is something wrong?
关于这些报告我有个疑问
I've got a question on these reports.
这些尸体都是在地下室发现的吗
Were they all found in the basement?
不 长官 大多数是地下室发现的
No, ma'am. We've been finding most in the basement,
可有一些是在上面发现的
but some are on the upper floors too.
你能不能把尸检报告写得更详细些  就当是为了我
Can you be specific in the 24s, for my sake anyway?
- 没问题 - 多谢
- No problem. - Thanks.
现在多少了
How many so far?
- 17起 - 天哪
- 17. - Christ.
好多红色的名字
That's a lot of red names.
这是你的第一次"红牛"
It's your first "Red Bull."
嗯 我以为第一次会是
Yeah. I thought I'd get a nice,
一两件安安静静的家庭纠纷
quiet domestic or two to start me off.
现在已经有国内媒体关注这个案件了
We got national press on this already.
你会没事的 Rhonnie
You'll be fine, Rhonnie.
只要别让别人看到你紧张就行
Just don't let any of these guys see you sweating.
嘿 我要撤诉一个案子
Hey, I need a case dropped.
要让Mello签字撤销  我需要一个友善的助理检察官
To tell Mello to sign off, I need a friendly A.S.A.
他踢破了一辆无线电通讯警车的窗户 你想放他走人吗
He kicks out a radio-car window, and you wanna give him a walk?
尸体的死亡时间范围怎样
What's the date range as per decomp?
Mount街上的这个看上去有大概一个礼拜
The one on Mount Street looked about a week.
有些是几天
Some a few days,
有些现阶段已成了骷髅
some are skeletal at this stage.
- 他们都是头部中枪吗 - 大多数都是多处中枪
- They all head shots? - Multiples, most of them.
- 男性黑人 15到25岁? - 嗯
- Black males, 15 to 25? - Uh-huh.
不 有的年纪更大些
No, some older.
这里有一个穿保安制服的
We got one in a security guard's uniform around here somewhere.
你们拍照扫描了吧 用吸尘器了吗
You laser-print? Vacuum the rooms?
是的
Yes.
测试过血迹了吧 地理分布怎样
Gluco for blood? What's the geography?
西区13个 Baltimore到Winchester
13 on West Side, Baltimore to Winchester,
Schroeder到Grove
Schroeder to the Grove.
东区在Monument街发现4个
The Eastern boys found four more in the houses on Monument Street.
- 东区? - 嗯 我们也被搞糊涂了
- East Side? - Yeah. That threw us.
我们现在撒网的范围更大了 在全市范围内排查空房屋
We're casting a wider net now, searching the vacants citywide.
在局里我的破案位次是23
My number's 23 in the office pool.
我还有希望
I still have hope.
这真他妈是个大案子
Hell of a case, right here.
如果我是警察
You know, if I was police,
我绝不能坐视不管 你呢
I don't think I could lean back on it. You?
- 如果我是真正的警察 绝对办不到 - 嗯
- Not if I was real police. - Right.
多谢了 警探
Thank you, Detective.
- Calvin 你已经做完了吗 - 嗯 做完了
- Calvin, you done already? - Yeah, I'm done.
提醒各位注意
Attention, a reminder:
测试结束后
Answer sheets must be turned into the office by you
答题纸必须立即
and only you
由本人交到办公室
immediately upon completion of the tests.
谢谢合作
Thank you for your cooperation.
钉枪调查进展如何
Where are we on the nail gun?
型号是Hilti DX
A Hilti DX model.
比较高端 但在承包商中很常见
High end, but common among contractors.
Hauk警官在Chris Partlow的卡车后面 看到的是这个吗
Is it what Sergeant Hauk saw in the back of Chris Partlow's truck?
我们给他看了一把同型号的钉枪 他认为他看到的就是这种
We showed him one, and he thought so.
然后我们带他去当时他停车的街区
Then we dragged his ass back down to the block where he did the car stop.
有线索吗
Anything?
我们发现一个疑似的洞
We found what might be a hole
他说他就是在那里用钉枪打洞的
where he said he fired into the street,
不过没找到钉子  用金属探测器搜查了整个街区 都没找到
but no nail, even after sweeping the block with metal detectors.
可能当时搞上了某个家伙的无线电通讯车
Probably took a ride in some bastard's radio,
现在在废旧轮胎堆里躺着呢
but now it's in a tire pile somewhere.
我们下一步是要搜寻并扣押那辆卡车
So our next move is a search and seizure on that truck.
并且申请庭谕化验Chris和Snoop的毛发和血液
Along with a court order for hair and blood from Chris and Snoop both.
我们从空房子里搜集了这么多物证
With everything we're pulling out these houses,
很有可能会发现线索
we might get lucky with some tracework.
- 合理根据是什么 - Herc看到钉枪了
- What's your P.C.? - Herc sees the nail gun.
持有一把建筑工具并不犯法
Nothing wrong with owning a power tool.
要求取Chris和Snoop的毛发和血样的具体理由是什么
What's the P.C. on Chris and Snoop specifically?
一个目击者
A witness--
有个男孩从同伙那里得知凶手是谁
the boy who was told by a co-conspirator who the murderer was.
那个男孩是信息源 他不是证人
The boy is a source. He's not a witness.
如果他只是信息源 理由就不够充分
If he's just a source, you don't have enough.
没错 可是再加上我们发现的
No, but with the links that we got
这些尸体和Stanfield以及他的组织之间的联系
between some of these bodies and Stanfield
我们就找到了一种规律
and his organization, we have a pattern.
理由不充分 一点也不充分
Weak. Very weak.
操
Oh, fuck it.
给我一个小时
Give me an hour.
你整个星期都在烦我
You haven't left me alone all week.
每次我从泳池上来 你都想把我擦干...
Every time I come out of the pool,
- Dennis Wise - 嘿 哥们
- Dennis Wise. - Hey, man.
你能传个话吗
Yeah. Were you able to get some word?
只要我发话 他就会乖乖地坐下来听你说话
On my say-so, he's willing to sit and hear you out.
不过你要求他做的事...难说啊
But what you asking him for-- I don't know.
还是祝你好运吧
Good luck, though.
如果你再见到我的小弟Carver
If you see my man Carver again,
你告诉他他欠我一个人情
you tell him he owe me one now.
- 好的 兄弟 多谢了 - 不客气 老兄
- All right, man. Appreciate it. - You got it, bro.
还你
All right.
你会带逮捕证回来吗
Y'all coming back with a warrant?
回来抓232号病房的无赖
The roughneck in room 232.
据我所知 他经营一家儿童健身房
From what I know, he runs a gym program for kids.
他是在劝一个孩子别堕落时被枪打伤的
He got himself shot for trying to pull a kid off the corner.
听着 你必须现在站出来说话
Look, you need to speak up now,
否则你就承认自己根本不敢说出真相
or face the fact that you never spoke at all.
游行的时候他们不准我去看我儿子
They wouldn't let me see my son at marches.
他们说 当我儿子被找到时  尸骨已所剩无几
Said there wasn't much left by the time y'all found him.
我们已经最大限度利用现有信息 帮你找儿子了
We did the best we could with the information we had.
我听说一个叫Chris的男人
Word come to me that a man named Chris
和一个叫Loop还是Snoop的姑娘
and a girl named Loop or Snoop
带走了我的儿子 并杀了他
or some such took my son and killed him.
他们说我再也见不到我儿子了
Told me I would never see my boy again.
你为什么就不能破个例
Why can't you just make an exception in this case
把他移到等待名单的第一位呢
and move his name to the top of the list,
尽快让别人收养他
see that he gets another foster parent?
名单就是名单
The list is the list.
有些申请者在孤儿院好几年了
Some clients have been in group homes for years.
他也在孤儿院呆了很多年
He was in group homes for years.
- 他现在凭什么回去 - 请不要对我吼
- Now he's gotta go back because--  - Please don't raise your voice.
- 如果你对我吼... - 拜托
- If you're going to raise your voice-- - Please.
一定有什么办法能让他不必回...
There's gotta be some way that he doesn't have to go--
是的 的确有一个办法
Yeah, there is.
这个肯定行
There's gotta be.
你说
How about--
我收养他如何
how about if I take him as a foster parent?
审查过程要持续3到4个月
The screening process takes three to four months.
这个孩子不能由你监护 警官
This child can't be in your custody, Sergeant.
按照青少年法规 他必须继续由我们监护
He needs to come back under our supervision per the juvenile order.
你就只有骚扰老百姓的本事吗
Think you all that for hassling niggers and shit?
是啊 没错
I know I'm all that.
我还想骚扰美女呢
I'm thinking about some pussy.
- 嗯 彼此彼此 - 呵
- Yeah. Me too. - Mm-hmm.
他们把工具都弃了
They dumped their tools.
座位下没有 车内工具箱里没有
Nothing under the seats. Nothing in the glove box.
毫无疑问 登记在案这是某位老太太的车
Registered to some little old lady, no doubt.
他们很懂行
These guys know the drill.
你能抓住这两位的把柄不
Can you see these two riding tail?
再找找
Come on.
操
shit.
找到了
There it is.
车都不是我们的
It ain't even our truck.
可我必须听你亲口说
But I need to hear it from you.
听我亲口说
From me:
其实这根本不关我的事
This is not my affair, huh?
Joe是这么说的 我也是为了Joe才来这里
It is what Joe says. I'm only here right now for Joe,
我信任他 我尊重他
who I trust, who I respect,
我和他合作多年
who I worked with for many years.
我对你不了解 也不需要了解
You I do not know, and I don't need to know.
可是因为Joe有了麻烦 所以...
But because this thing goes wrong for Joe, then--
我怎么知道这不是陷阱
Well, how am I supposed to know this ain't no setup?
我怎么知道你们不是一伙的
How am I supposed to know your people ain't in on it too?
因为Joe是这么说的
You know because Joe says
因为我是这么说的
and because I say.
你就这么相信人吗
And you trust your people like that?
我和会我的司机交心而谈
I talked to my driver.
我能直视他的灵魂
I looked into his soul.
Chris和Snoop因车里
Chris and Snoop just been popped
藏着非法枪支被捕
on a gun charge, found in the truck.
打电话给保证人
Call the bondsman.
不过首先 你还是找人盯住他
But first, put a follow on him right there.
谁 那个戴帽子的白种人吗
Who, white dude with the hat on?
他是个麻烦的家伙吗
What, he a problem?
不 我只是需要多了解他的情况
I just need to know more.
- 行 - 好的
- All right. - All right.
满意了吧
Satisfied?
明早给你9万美金
$90,000 to you in the morning.
之后会找人搜寻Omar
We'll put a hunt on Omar later,
等沸沸扬扬的空房子事件的风头过去之后
after the heat on them empty houses gives way.
巴尔的摩中央登记和收容中心 释放出口
你他妈的来干嘛
The fuck are you doing here?
你以为没人给你特殊照顾
You think that charge gets dropped
就能轻易撤诉吗
without somebody showing you some special love?
你饿不饿
You hungry?
走吧
Come on.
好 Chris Partlow可能有履约保证
All right. Might be surety bond on this Chris Partlow,
因为他有前科
given all of his priors.
那个叫Pearson的女人 就不是这回事儿了 知道了吗
Pearson woman-- not so much. All right?
这是干嘛
What's this?
庭谕 我们要取你们的血液和毛发样本
Court order. We get blood and hair.
14根头发 14根体毛
14 head hairs, 14 body hairs,
两个各取两份血液样本
two blood samples each.
这么多房子 这么多谋杀
It's a lot of houses, a lot of deeds.
谁知道会留下什么蛛丝马迹呢
Who knows what you left behind?
我们还在市里吗
We still in the city?
Cylburn Arboretum Pimlico就在那座山上
Cylburn Arboretum. Pimlico's right up the hill.
这里真漂亮
This is nice.
我不会告密
I ain't no snitch.
没说你是
I didn't say you were.
我入行很久了
I've been doing this a long time.
我从不向条子告密
I ain't never said nothing to no cop.
我感觉我老了
I feel old.
我13岁就出来混了
I been out there since I was 13.
从来没算错帐 从来没偷货
I ain't never fucked up a count, never stole off a package,
从来没干过不该干的事
never did some shit that I wasn't told to do.
我老老实实地做了半辈子 可结果呢
I've been straight up. But what come back,
如果我遇上麻烦
You think if I get jammed up on some shit,
他们会说 "嗯 反正Bodie也不是第一次了"
they'd be like, "All right, yeah. Bodie been there."
"Bodie坚持住了  我们会请律师的 我们会保你出来的"
"Bodie hang tough. We got his pay lawyer.We got a bail."
他们想让我和他们站在一边
They want me to stand with them, right?
可是当情况变得糟糕
But where the fuck they at, when
不可收拾的时候 他们又他妈的在哪里呢
I mean, when shit goes bad and there's hell to pay,
他们在哪里呢
where they at?
这个游戏被人操控了啊 哥们
This game is rigged, man.
我们就像棋盘上的棋子
We like the little bitches on a chessboard.
小卒
Pawns.
我不会去出卖我兄弟们的
Yo, I'm not snitching on none of my boys--
我那块区域的人 我都不会
not my corner, and not no Barksdale people,
还有Barksdale的余党
or what's left of them.
可是Marlo 这个小子和他的同伙 哥们
But Marlo-- this nigger and his kind, man,
他们必须被清除 必须的
they gotta fall. They gotta.
为此 必须有人站出来提供线索
Well, for that to happen, somebody's gotta step up.
我尽力而为吧 我才不在乎呢
I'll do what I gotta. I don't give a fuck.
只是别他妈强迫我低三下四的
Just don't ask me to live on my fucking knees, you know?
你是个勇士 Bodie
You're a soldier, Bodie.
可不是吗
Hell, yeah.
我记得你
I remember you.
你曾是Pennsie和Fremont的头儿
You used to be a roll-up on Pennsie and Fremont.
嗯 那是我曾经的岗位
Yeah. It was my old post.
- 我因为C.B.S.坐牢 - Calhoun Baker Stricker
- I came up with C.B.S. - Calhoun, Baker, Stricker.
是啊 我以前不得不经常找你们的麻烦
Yeah. I used to have to bang up on y'all all the time.
这个我也记得
I remember that too.
嗯 不过现在我不是警察了
Yeah. I ain't a cop now, right?
我是说 就像我告诉Cutty的一样
I mean, like I told Cutty,
我现在是老师了
I'm sort of like a teacher now,
我也是这样认识Namond的
and that's how I come to know Namond.
我坐在这里和你谈 只是因为Cutty开了口
Only reason I'm even here is Cutty spoke for you.
他说了我为何而来吗
He say what I'm asking?
你的儿子...
Your boy...
很聪明 很风趣
is smart and funny
也很外向
and open-hearted,
他很有潜力
and he got some flex in him.
刚开始我没看出来 因为他总是很调皮
And I ain't see it at first, 'cause he was always acting out,
满嘴街头粗话
always full up of corner talk--
他这样做只是在掩饰内心
you know, just talking shit to hide himself.
可是他这辈子能去很多地方 能干很多大事
But he could go a lot of places and do a lot of things in his life,
他会活得精彩
be out there in the world in a way that,
有一个和你我完全不同的人生
you know, didn't happen for you and me.
我是说 我们这种人 他妈的
I mean, you know, our kind? Shit.
哥们 我们一直到死只知道
Man, we both know we gonna go to our grave forever knowing
Bentalou最边缘的街区叫什么
what block Bentalou dead-ends at,
谁从黑市购买贩酒许可证
or who got their liquor license over at the Underground,
88年Taterman从音乐厅里出来时
or what corner Tater man got shot on
是在哪个街角遇害
when he come out the Musical Lounge back in '88.
那些流金岁月啊
It's a vision in gold.
我们所知道的西区
The West Side we knew--
已经死气沉沉了 哥们
it's dead, man.
现在掌权的人
You know, people in the game nowadays--
我是说 已经和从前完全不同了
I mean, it's a whole different breed--
无原则 无家庭
no code, no family,
必然也就无尊重
and damn sure no respect.
我是说 你现在把Namond送到街上去贩毒
I mean, you send Namond out on the corner now,
那么可能
I'm giving him
2年后他就进停尸房了
maybe one, two years before he down at the morgue.
或者 如果幸运的话 和你一样蹲牢房
And maybe, if you're lucky, up here with you.
或许这样 或许那样 世事本就难料
Maybe, maybe not. That's the game.
我现在说的是Namond Brice先生
I'm talking about Namond here, Mr. Brice.
他可以成就很多 成就很多伟大的事情
He's a lot of things, a lot of good things.
我是说 只要给他一丁点机会  他可能就会出其不意地给我们惊喜
I mean, before you know, he might surprise all of us given half a chance,
可他天生不是去街头贩毒的 哥们
but he ain't made for them corners, man.
我是说 不像我们
I mean, not like we were.
我来这里就是因为 我要让你明白这一点
That's why I come down here because I gotta believe that you see it,
毕竟你是经历过的人
being who you are and all you've been through.
你了解你儿子
You know your son.
哥们 一切全看你决定了
It's in your hands, man.
你的要求太高了
You asking too much.
是的 但我坚持我的要求
Yeah, but I'm asking.
你确定那个人是Bodie吗
You sure it was the boy Bodie?
哥们 我看他从Eager街的
Man, I seen him come from out the Central Booking
拘留中心出来
over on Eager Street side.
然后和一个白人上了车
Then he got in some car with some white dude.
警车吗 什么车 一辆Caprice?
Police? What kind of car, a Caprice?
不 我想是一辆Hooptie
No, a hooptie, I think.
他们操他妈的就和你干上了
They on you like a motherfucker.
他们抓了你  把你在那些房子里干的事儿都揪了出来
They jacking you up, pulling all your work out them houses, right?
哥们 现在我们可和探子耗不起
Man, we can't have nobody snitching on us now.
我们还不能确定
We ain't sure it's that.
你想就这么算了吗 那就风险自担
What, you wanna let it go? Risk it?
要杀鸡儆猴
Huh-uh. Send a message.
你可以交给你的小弟去干 让他练练手
Maybe give it to your pup, get him started.
你和Snoop 在事情平息前你们低调行事
You and Snoop, y'all lay low till this shit here blow down.
那孩子曾是Bodie的手下
Boy worked for Bodie.
第一次动手 最好是他不认识的
First time, best be someone he ain't know.
你听到Joe说的了吗
You hear what Joe said?
Joe说那个偷我们货的吃鸡巴的
Joe's saying this cocksucker who stole our shit
想以3折卖回给我们
wanna sell it back to us for 30 on the dollar.
Joe说要买回我们那一份还要90万美元
Joe's saying it's another 90 to buy back our share.
哥们 还以为你把我忘了呢
Dag, yo. Thought you forgot about me.
嘿 你为什么不去外面等着呢
Hey, why don't you wait outside, all right?
你和他爸谈过了吗
You spoke to his father?
如果我没弄错的话
If it goes the way I think,
他明天会和他母亲一起过来
he'll be back with his mom by tomorrow.
明天是个重要的日子
Big day all around tomorrow.
Watkins委员为我们争取到30分钟 去市长办公室汇报工作
Delegate Watkins got us 30 minutes at the mayor's office.
白面!
Icicles!
再不买就没了! 白面!
Get 'em while it's going! Icicles!
快来买啊!
Come on!
蜘蛛 卖了多少了
Yo, Spider, what's the count?
哥们 我可不认为今天我们卖得完
I don't even think we gonna sell out today, man.
白面! 白面!
Icicles! Icicles!
嘿Bodie 嘿Bodie
Yo, Bodie, Yo, Bodie,
白面! 有白面!
Icicles!Icicles!
嘿 Bodie 你还是赶紧闪吧
Yo, Bodie, you better run, yo.
这是我的地盘 我哪儿都不去
Yo, this my corner. I ain't running nowhere.
Bodie 你疯了吗
Bodie, is you crazy?
开战吧!
Shit is on!
接招吧 操蛋的! 我他妈才不怕呢!
Run with it, motherfuckers! I don't give a fuck!
老子在这儿呢!
I'm right here!
你们不能把我抛尸废弃房屋
You ain't putting me up in one of them empty-ass houses, neither.
Bodie 走吧 哥们
Bodie, come on, man.
真不知道会怎么样
I don't know about this.
市长办公室 是的
Mayor's office. Yes.
事实上 你应该去找住房社区发展部...
Actually, you want the Department of Housing and Community Development.
听着 哥们 我完全没有把握 我...
Look, I don't know about this, man. I just...
女士...
Ma'am...
如果... 对不起
if... sorry.
如果市长不想...
If the mayor prefers not to--
如果他...想让Parenti博士单独和他说...
if he, like, feels more comfortable with Dr. Parenti alone,
因为去年毒品合法化之争的事情...
you know because of the drug-legalization controversy last year...
我认为Carcetti市长不会参加您的会议  他在安纳波利斯
I don't think Mayor Carcetti is in your meeting. He's in Annapolis.
好的 谢谢
Okay. Thank you.
好啊
What up?
还没睡醒呢
Still asleep?
早起的鸟儿有虫吃
Early bird get that worm.
觉得这房子怎样
How you liking the crib?
挺好的 多谢关心
Fine, thanks.
自立的感觉一定很棒
Must feel good to be on your own.
这戒指哪里来的
Yo, where you get that ring from?
从别人那里拿来的
Took it from a nigger.
怎么 你想要
Why? You want it?
不 不 你留着吧 小子
Nah nah. You keep it, Shorty.
我帮Bug做上学前准备
I'll go get Bug ready for school.
你准备好干活了吗
You ready to put in work?
两件事
Two things then:
第一 我们会给你Payson的街角
First, we're gonna give you the corner up on Payson.
那曾是Bodie的地盘 现在归你了
Used to be Bodie's old corner. Now it's yours.
组织好人马 把那一块管好了
Crew that up. Run that shit.
你就会有好分成
You get the points on that shop.
还有一件事
Then we got this other thing.
冒昧问一句
Yo, if I ain't stepping on nothing,
你让我们除掉的那个人是谁啊
who was that who dropped for you, yo?
- Bug他爹 - 什么
- Bug's daddy. - Word?
"paraphernalia"（用具)不是这样拼的
That's not how you spell "paraphernalia."
- 你他妈怎么拼啊 - 嘿 伙计们
- How the fuck do you spell it? - Hey, fellas.
反正不是这样拼 McNulty 嘿
Not like that. McNulty. Hey.
你轮班是4:00到12:00 是吧  你听说Bodie的事了吗
You're here 4:00 to 12:00, right? You heard about Bodie?
- 什么事  - Bodie Payson的 - 知道知道 什么情况
- What about? Yeah yeah. What? - Bodie, from up Payson.
在他的地盘上被杀了
Shot dead on his corner.
是值夜班的警员发现的 看看报告吧
Midnight shift caught it. Check the readout.
警司 快滚进来
Sergeant, get your ass in here.
该死 警司 你这简直就是违抗命令
God damn it, Sergeant, you're on the brink of insubordination.
你马上给社会福利部打电话  把他送走 这是命令
You call D.S.S. right now and ship him out. That's an order.
警督
Lieutenant--
我有235美元 或许有用
I got $235, if it helps.
这有什么用呢
How would that help:
或许我们可以用钱买通别人收养我
Maybe we can get a foster spot like that-- pay somebody.
说白了 不就是分班吗
This is tracking, plain and simple.
不 不是的 这是一个社会化过程
No, it isn't. it's a socialization process.
可是有些家长会抱怨说 这就是把好坏学生分开
But to any parent who complains, you're still segregating them.
可这... 这是为了他们好
But I mean... it's for their benefit,
也是为了努力教书的教师们好
and for the benefit of the teachers trying to teach.
你们建议把这种模式推广到每一所初中?
And you're proposing to expand this to every middle school?
如果有足够的经费和支持  我们会在9月之前
With enough grant money and your support, yes.
全面推行
By September.
不过你们不会教授考试内容吗
But you wouldn't be teaching test curriculum here?
他们可以说是后进生
These would be the children left behind, so to speak.
没错 不过事实上
Yeah, but as it is, I mean,
所有学生都是后进生 我们只是不想承认而已
we're leaving them all behind anyway. We just don't want to admit it.
- 我们想说的是... - 先生们...
- What we mean to say is-- - Gentlemen...
我们再联系
we'll be in touch.
啥 这样就算完了吗
So what, that's it?
才听了2分钟 就把我们一票否决了吗
After a two-minute hearing, they stick a fork in us?
哥们 他们都看我不顺眼
I'm a liability in there, man.
在这个城市里 我每次开口说话
Seems like every time I open my mouth in this town,
我都尽说些别人不想听的
I'm telling people something they don't want to know.
- 不是你的缘故 这是一个过程 - 过程?
- It's not you. It's the process. - The process?
我们拿到经费后 我们研究问题 我们提出解决方案
When we get the grant, we study the problem, we propose solutions.
如果他们愿意听 那就听
If they listen, they listen.
如果不愿意听 那还是很好的研究成果
If they don't, it still makes for great research.
这个问题的研究成果出版后 一定会引起关注
What we publish on this is gonna get a lot of attention.
- 谁的关注 - 研究员 学者
- From who: - From other researchers, academics.
学者?
Academics?
怎么 他们会研究别人的研究成果?
What, they gonna study your study?
这风气啥时才能变呢
When do this shit change?
你让他出去贩毒了啊
And you put him out, huh?
他必须变得坚强
He need to get hard.
我说让你放手 你就放手
Well, if he out, then he out.
不 才不要
Oh, no, you're not.
你不能把我儿子带走 这次不行...
You ain't gonna take my son away from me, not for this--
记住你在和谁说话
Remember who the fuck you talking to right here.
记住我的身份
Remember who I am.
我的话还是有分量的
My word is still my word.
在这里 在巴尔的摩
In here, in Baltimore,
有任何你可以称为家的地方
and in any place you can think of calling home,
我说话算数 他们会找到你的
it'll be my word. They'll find you.
有个人专程跑来跟我说 我儿子能成为任何他想成为的人
Man come down here to say my son can be anything he damn please.
除了勇士
Except a soldier.
你瞧瞧我
Yeah, well, look at me up in here.
如果一个人能心想事成
Who the fuck would want to be that
谁他妈的愿意去拼命 De'Londa?
if they could be anything else, De'Londa?
那么...
So...
你是不是也不要我了
did you cut me off too?
我还是和你在一起 我们能继续过日子
You still got me. We'll get by.
不过你一定放让我儿子走
But you gonna let go of that boy.
务必
Bet that.
谁
Quien es?
是我Omar 宝贝
It's Omar, baby.
这是存银行的吗
For your bank?
这是给您的辛苦费 Butch  我可以自己开银行了
That's for your pain, Butch. I be my own bank now.
没人跟着你吧
They ain't follow you?
没有 Joe按照我的要求付了钱
Nah. Joe paid it my way.
他必须承认我的话比他的话有分量 你懂吗
He had to admit my word was better than his. You feel me?
我们走
Let's go then.
他在货车里
He is in the van,
车停在Polk街2249号后面的车库
in the garage in the back of 2249 Polk Street.
钥匙在碎石堆里
The key gonna be in the cinderblock.
你偷了这么多
You steal this much,
事情一定没完
and this ain't over.
This ain't over.
那个共和党的混球
Thing about that Republican ass,
他根本就是婊子养的
it's not the flesh of his political fathers.
天啊
Jesus.
- 你和他摊牌了 - 他妈的小人
- You left it on the table. - Smug son of a bitch.
他要我求他
He was gonna make me beg,
再召开新闻发布会 让全世界的人都看我低声下气地求他
then call a press conference so the world could see me on my knees.
别担心
Don't worry.
2年后 我们会让他付出代价的
Two years, and we'll make him pay.
白面 白面! 买白面咯!
Icicle, icicle! Got those icicles!
条子来了!
Shakedown!
这个街角被和谐了 快走人 都散了
Corner's indicted. Go on. Get.
除了你 操蛋的 趴墙上
Except you, motherfucker. On the wall.
Bodie的事我很抱歉
Sorry about Bodie.
我不是要抓你 我是想为他伸张正义
I ain't jacking you up. I'm trying to do right for your boy.
- 是谁害死了他 - 是你们
- Who dropped him? - Y'all did.
就因为他和你们说话 他才被杀的
They took him out 'cause he was talking to y'all.
传说有人在拘留中心看见他和警察在一起
Word is they seen him with the police down at Central Booking.
所以说要么把我拷走
So cuff me
要么在重蹈覆辙前放我离开
or kick my ass off this corner before you do me the same.
嘿 Duquan
Hey, Duquan.
你不是要去Douglass吗
Don't you need to be at Douglass?
我正要去呢
I'm on my way there, yeah.
你的书包呢
Where's your book bag?
哦 这个...我会回家一趟取书包
Oh, it's-- I'm gonna stop past the house and get it.
这礼物送你 感谢你做的一切
It's a present for all you did.
这个用来装饰你的桌子
It's for your desk.
真好看 Duquan 多谢
That's great, Duquan. Thanks.
经常来坐坐
Stop past anytime,
和我聊聊你的近况
Let me know how it's going with you.
好的
Okay.
- 可我不想回去 - 项目结束了 Zenobia
- But I ain't want to go back. - Program's ending, Zenobia.
好家伙 又可以跟大家一起了
Yeah, boy. Back to gen pop.
耶
Yes.
赶紧收拾走人
Pack my bags.
你怎么想
What about you?
我觉得 这个项目挺好...
I mean, this was all right...
不过 是时候离开了
but maybe it's time.
你怎么醒了
Why are you up?
你值的是4:00到12:00的班 怎么了
You're working 4:00 to 12:00. What's the matter?
是关于那些尸体的事情
Something with these bodies.
Lester他们正在调查
Lester and them are getting up on it.
这件事归Daniels管
It's under Daniels.
他现在受到上司青睐
He's got suction now.
他可以说到做到
He can deliver.
你想加入他们
You want in.
我现在觉得自己欠别人的
I just feel like I owe it now.
欠谁
To who?
欠一个孩子 街角的孩子
To this kid. Corner kid.
原本想让他做线人
Getting ready to turn him, you know,
把他包起来 作为礼物送给Lester
wrap him up and give him to Lester as a present.
他的尸体也被丢在空房子里吗
He one of the bodies in the houses:
不 被扔在大街上
No, they dropped him in the street.
- 或许我会变得不同 - 不同
- Maybe I'd be different, you know? - Different:
不再...
Yeah, no more of the...
酗酒 不再乱性 不再乱发脾气
drinking and the whoring and all that. All that anger.
因为和你在一起 我就变得更好了
'Cause I'm better now here with you.
不再和世人玩 "蛋疼的Jimmy" 了
No more playing "Jimmy Bust Balls" with the world.
"蛋疼的Jimmy"?
"Jimmy Bust Balls"?
我向上天发誓 Beadie  那狗娘养的差点把我害死
I swear to God, Beadie, that son of a bitch nearly killed me.
没关系
It's okay.
- 什么 - 你尽力了
- What? - You tried.
你不必自责
You don't need to feel bad.
多谢
Thanks.
好了 Randy 这边走
All right, Randy, this way.
那边的上铺归你
Take that top bunk over there.
警察
Five-0.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
我这样问 不是因为我不能用你
I'm not asking 'cause I can't use you.
我这样问是为了你好
I'm asking for your sake.
我认为我能担当此任 不让我成为我自己
I think I can do this and keep myself away from myself,
如果你懂我的意思
if that makes any sense.
可我得告诉你
But I gotta tell you,
我们不能让Marlo Stanfield团伙 在街上晃荡
we're not gonna get Marlo Stanfield or anyone else
不能让他们在街上胡来
above the street, not on street rips.
你想怎么做
What do you suggest?
要么扩大线人范围 要么再度监听
Either a wide C.I. or a Title lll.
这样才能破案
That's what makes this case.
你确定吗
You sure?
或许你可以迅速 简单 干净利落地完事
Maybe you do this fast and clean and simple.
那就相当于没做
Then you don't do it at all.
听你的啊 副总警监
Chain of command, Colonel.
我们怎么可能同时提高
How in the hell do we kick up percentages
数学和阅读的百分率呢
in math and reading both?
你相信这些数据吗
You believe the numbers?
38%良好 8% 优秀
38% proficient. 8% advanced.
什么
What?
"良好" 是说他们比平均水平低两级
"Proficient" means they're at least two grades below their level.
"优秀" 是说他们达到平均水平 或落后一年
"Advanced" can mean they're at grade level or a year below.
分数是这样打出来的 所以...
They score 'em like that, and...
所以 他们说我们在进步
they say we're making progress.
好的 我还在熟悉情况
Okay. I'm still learning.
很快你就会明白了
Nah, you're gonna be fine.
Albert Zenobia Namond 欢迎回来
Albert, Zenobia, Namond, good to have you back with us.
是啊 你最可怕的梦魇又回来了
Yeah. Your worst nightmare come right back on you.
没有啦 我说笑呢
Say, no, I'm just foolin'.
好了 大家翻到121页
Okay. Everyone open to 121.
谁算出了第一题
Who figured out the first problem?
- Kareem - 164 - 正确
- Kareem? Correct. - 164.
- 你怎么算出来的 - 不知道 - 上来 算给我们看
- How'd you get it? Come. Show us. - Don't know.
还以为完事了呢
Just when you think you're done.
多少了 20?
What's that one? 20?
22 有Bunk的消息吗
22. Anybody heard from Bunk?
弹道科说没有和枪匹配的子弹 线索又断了
Ballistics say the guns match to nothing. Opened and closed.
指纹也被抹掉了
And they cleaned the prints.
或许我们会找到证人
Well, maybe we find a witness.
或许痕迹实验室会找出一根毛发  一些液体之类的
Maybe trace lab gives us a hair or splatter or something.
就算没有 我们也要保持积极态度
But short of that, we're gonna have to go proactive.
最新发现的尸体调查进展如何
Where are you on the new body?
又回到了原点 我们要打持久战
Back to square one. We're in here for the long haul.
副总警监 你为什么选这个地方安排调查此案
Colonel, how'd you happen to pick this place for us to stage?
Lemel 这个地方几年前关了
Lemel: They closed it a few years back,
我知道这里离很多犯罪现场很近
and I knew it was near a lot of our crime scenes.
我曾经在这里上过学
I went to school here back in the day.
现在想起来 当时的确是受到良好的教育
Got a decent education, now that I think on it.
你和他谈了吗
You try and talk to him?
我不知道该说些什么  我今早才从警司那里知道的
Didn't know what to say. Only heard from my sergeant this morning.
我想我是漏看了这个案件的报告
Guess I missed the 24 they wrote on it.
他真的尝试过自杀吗  不只是表演给别人看吗
And he really tried to do himself? It wasn't just for show or nothing?
Bub有很多缺点
Bub's got some problems,
虚伪不是其一
but insincerity ain't one of them.
羞耻心是个微妙的东西 是吧
Shame's some tricky shit, ain't it?
让你有改变的冲动
Makes you feel like you want to change,
当你认为自己改变不了的时候  狠狠地打击你
and then beats you back down when think you can't.
你们最近一次谈话是什么时候
When was the last time y'all talked?
几年前吧 我想是他上一次戒毒的时候
More than a couple of years, since he last got on the wagon, I think.
如果他现在在D病区  那他比婴儿还干净纯洁
If he's up in D ward, he's cleaner than a motherfucker right now.
你来吗
You coming?
你先去吧
Maybe later.
学校预算危机
我不敢相信 他就放弃了那笔钱
Can't believe he'd leave that money on the table.
不该放弃吗
Why not?
学校 孩子
School. Kids.
该死
Shit.
你还没干够呢
You ain't done enough of this here, I suppose.
他们总是令你失望
They always disappoint.
你离他们越近 你看到的越多
Closer you get, more you look--
他们都一样
all of them.
你明年投奔谁
Who you going with next year?
如果他想竞选Elijah的岗位  我会和Royce在一起
If he tries for Elijah's seat, I might stay with Royce.
如果不是的话
If not,
Salisbury有个年轻人
there's this young buck out in Salisbury
认为他可以抢到第一把交椅
thinks he can snatch up the First District seat.
槲寄生 来买啊
Mistletoe. Come get 'em.
槲寄生!
Mistletoe!
你可以看着他的眼睛
You can look him in the eye now.
不论他是谁 干了什么 你都直视他的双眼
No matter who he is or what he's done, you look him right in the eye.
我还是你的父亲
I'm still your father.
无名氏
Marlo Stanfield
你想干嘛
What you want?
告密的贱人
身体右侧
Right to the body.
这就对了 动起来 眼睛看哪儿呢
That's right. Keep it moving. Where your eyes at?
看哪儿呢 在看什么呢
Where you looking-- what you looking at?
嘿
Hey!
你们不能在这里玩
You cannot be out here.
去找些有用的事做
Y'all need to find something constructive to do with yourselves.
快去
Go on.
Michael
Michael.
枪
The gun.
你要迟到了
Na', you're gonna be late.
快走 走吧
Go on. Go.
孩子 你的盘子呢
Boy, where's your plate?
Tyrell 等等
Yo, Tyrell, wait up.
Robert F. Colesberry 1947-2004 （本剧制片人)
风软FRM字幕组作品  欢迎加入
welcome to www.1000fr.net